In the last video we talked
在我们谈到的上一个视频（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 黄海广 haiguang2000@qq.com）
about the Multivariate Gaussian Distribution
关于多元高斯分布
and saw some examples of the
，看到的一些
sorts of distributions you can model, as
建立的各种分布模型，
you vary the parameters, mu and sigma.
当你改变参数，mu和sigma。
In this video, let's take those
在这段视频中，让我们这些
ideas, and apply them
想法，并应用它们
to develop a different anomaly detection algorithm.
制定一个不同的异常检测算法。
To recap the multivariate Gaussian
要回顾一下多元高斯
distribution and the multivariate normal
分布和多元正态分布
distribution has two parameters, mu and sigma.
分布有两个参数，mu和sigma。
Where mu this an n
其中mu这一个n
dimensional vector and sigma,
维向量和sigma，
the covariance matrix, is an
的协方差矩阵，是一种
n by n matrix.
n乘n的矩阵。
And here's the formula for
而这里的公式
the probability of X, as
X的概率，如
parameterized by mu and
按mu和参数化
sigma, and as you
sigma，和你的
vary mu and sigma, you
变量mu和sigma，你
can get a range of different
可以得到一个范围的不同
distributions, like, you know,
分布一样，你知道的，
these are three examples of the
这些都是三个样本
ones that we saw in the previous video.
那些我们在以前的视频看了。
So let's talk about the
因此，让我们谈谈
parameter fitting or the
参数拟合或
parameter estimation problem. The
参数估计问题。该
question, as usual, is if
问题，像往常一样，如果是
I have a set of examples
我有一组样本
X1 through XM and here each
X1到XM并且这里的每个
of these examples is an
这些样本是一个
n dimensional vector and I think my
n维向量，我想我的
examples come from a multivariate Gaussian distribution.
样本来自一个多元高斯分布。
How do I try to estimate my parameters mu and sigma?
我如何尝试估计我的参数mu和sigma？
Well the standard formulas for
以及标准公式的
estimating them is you
估计是：你
set mu to be just
设置mu是
the average of your training examples.
你的训练样本的平均值。
And you set sigma to be equal to this.
并设置sigma等于这一点。
And this is actually just
这其实只是
like the sigma that we had
像我们有sigma
written out, when we were
写出来，当我们
using the PCA or
使用PCA即
the Principal Components Analysis algorithm.
主成分分析算法。
So you just plug in these
所以你只需插入这
two formulas and this
两个公式，这
would give you your estimated parameter
会给你你估计的参数
mu and your estimated parameter sigma.
mu和你估计的参数sigma。
So given the data set here is how you estimate mu and sigma.
所以，这里给出的数据集是你如何估计mu和sigma。
Let's take this method
让我们以这种方法
and just plug it
而只需将其插入
into an anomaly detection algorithm.
到异常检测算法。
So how do we
那么，我们如何
put all of this together to
把所有这一切共同
develop an anomaly detection algorithm?
开发一个异常检测算法？
Here 's what we do.
下面是我们做什么。
First we take our training
首先，我们把我们的训练
set, and we fit the
集，和我们的拟合
model, we fit P
模型，我们计算P
of X, by, you know, setting
的X，要知道，设定
mu and sigma as described
mu和描述的一样sigma
on the previous slide.
在上一张幻灯片。
Next when you are given
您将得到下一个
a new example X. So
一个新的样本X，所以
if you are given a test example,
如果给你一个测试的样本，
lets take an earlier example to have a new example out here.
让作为一个早期的样本有一个新的样本在这里。
And that is my test example.
那是我的测试样本。
Given the new example X, what
鉴于新的样本X，
we are going to do is compute
我们要做的是计算
P of X, using this
p(x)，用这
formula for the multivariate Gaussian distribution.
式为多元高斯分布。
And then, if P of
然后，如果p(x)
X is very small, then we
是非常小的，那么我们
flagged it as an anomaly,
把它当作一个异常，
whereas, if P of X is greater
然而，如果p(x)是远大于
than that parameter epsilon, then
参数epsilon，则
we don't flag it as an anomaly.
我们不会将其标记为异常。
So it turns out, if we were to fit a multivariate Gaussian distribution to this data set,
所以，事实证明，如果我们要拟合多元高斯分布到这组数据，
so just the red crosses, not the green example,
所以只是图中的红叉，不是绿的样本，
you end up with a Gaussian
你完成了一个高斯
distribution that places lots
分布的地方很多
of probability in the central
在中央的概率
region, slightly less probability here,
区域，这里概率稍微小，
slightly less probability here,
在这里概率略少，
and very low probability at the point that is way out here.
并在该点是在这里的概率非常低。
And so, if you apply
所以，如果你应用
the multivariate Gaussian distribution to
多元高斯分布
this example, it will actually
本例中，将实际
correctly flag that example.
正确地标记样本。
as an anomaly.
作为一个异常。
Finally it's worth saying
最后，值得一说
a few words about what is
简要描述
the relationship between the
他们之间的关系：
multivariate Gaussian distribution model, and
多元高斯分布模型和
the original model, where we
原始模型，在那里我们
were modeling P(x)
被建模的P
X as a product of this
作为该商品
P of X1, P of X2,
P(X1)，P(X2)，
up to P of Xn.
到P(Xn)。
It turns out that you can
事实证明，你可以
prove mathematically, I'm not
数学上证明，我不是
going to do the proof here, but
要在这里做了证明，但
you can prove mathematically that this
你能证明在数学上，这
relationship, between the
关系，之间的
multivariate Gaussian model and
多元高斯模型和
this original one. And in
这种原始模型。而且
particular, it turns out
特别是，它原来
that the original model corresponds
原模型对应
to multivariate Gaussians, where
以多变量高斯，其中
the contours of the
的轮廓
Gaussian are always axis aligned.
高斯总是轴线对齐。
So all three of
因此，所有三个
these are examples of
这些样本
Gaussian distributions that you
高斯分布，你
can fit using the original model.
可以适合使用原始模型。
It turns out that that corresponds
原来，对应
to multivariate Gaussian, where, you
以多元高斯，在那里，你
know, the ellipsis here, the contours
知道，这里的省略号，轮廓
of this distribution--it
这种分布的 - 它
turns out that this model actually
事实证明，这种模式实际上
corresponds to a special
对应于一个特殊的
case of a multivariate Gaussian distribution.
情况下的多元高斯分布。
And in particular, this special
特别是，这个特殊的
case is defined by constraining
例子通过约束定义
the distribution of p
p(x)分布
of x, the multivariate a Gaussian
，多元高斯
distribution of p of x,
分布的p(x)，
so that the contours of
这个
the probability density function, of
概率密度函数的轮廓，
the probability distribution function, are axis aligned.
这个概率分布函数，是轴对齐。
And so you can get a p
所以你可以得到p(x)
of x with a
是一个
multivariate Gaussian that looks like
多元高斯分布，看起来像
this, or like this, or like this.
这样，或者这样，或者像这样。
And you notice, that in all
而且你注意到，在所有
3 of these examples, these ellipses,
第三个样本中，这些椭圆
or these ovals that I'm drawing, have
或者，这些椭圆形的我画，有
their axes aligned with the X1 X2 axes.
其轴线对准X1 X2轴。
And what we do not have, is
而我们没有，是
a set of contours
一组轮廓
that are at an angle, right?
这是一个角度，对不对？
And this corresponded to examples where
与此相对应的样本在那里
sigma is equal to 1 1, 0.8, 0.8.
sigma等于1 1，0.8，0.8。
Let's say, with non-0 elements on the
比方说，对非0元素
off diagonals.
关闭对角线。
So, it turns out that
所以，事实证明，
it's possible to show mathematically that
它是可能的数学证明
this model actually is the
这种模式实际上是
same as a multivariate Gaussian
同样作为多元高斯
distribution but with a constraint.
分布但有限制。
And the constraint is that the
约束是
covariance matrix sigma must
协方差矩阵sigma必须
have 0's on the off diagonal elements.
有0的对非对角元素。
In particular, the covariance matrix sigma,
特别地，协方差矩阵Σ和
this thing here, it would
这个东西在这里，它会
be sigma squared 1, sigma
被sigma平方1，sigma
squared 2, down to sigma
平方2，下至sigma
squared n, and then
平方N，然后
everything on the off diagonal
一切都在对角线关闭
entries, all of these elements
条目，所有这些元素
above and below the diagonal of the matrix,
上面和下面的对角矩阵，
all of those are going to be zero.
所有这些都将是零。
And in fact if you take
而事实上，如果你拿
these values of sigma, sigma
那些sigma的值，sigma
squared 1, sigma squared 2,
平方1，sigma平方2，
down to sigma squared n,
下降到sigma平方N，
and plug them into here, and
并将其插入在这里，
you know, plug them into this
你知道，将它们插入此
covariance matrix, then the
协方差矩阵，则
two models are actually identical.
两个模型实际上是相同的。
That is, this new model,
也就是说，这种新的模型，
using a multivariate Gaussian distribution,
使用多变量高斯分布，
corresponds exactly to the
完全对应
old model, if the covariance
旧的模式，如果协方差
matrix sigma, has only
矩阵的标准差，只有
0 elements off the diagonals,
0元折对角线，
and in pictures that
并且在图片的
corresponds to having Gaussian distributions,
对应于具有高斯分布，
where the contours of this
其中该轮廓
distribution function are axis aligned.
分布函数轴线对齐。
So you aren't allowed to model the correlations between the diffrent features.
所以你不允许模型的不同特征之间的相关性。
So in that sense the original model
所以在这个意义上的原始模型
is actually a special case of this multivariate Gaussian model.
其实这个多元高斯模型的一个特例。
So when would you use each of these two models?
你什么时候会使用这两类模型？
So when would you the original
所以，当你的原始
model and when would you use
模型，你会用时
the multivariate Gaussian model?
多变量高斯模型？
The original model is probably
原始模型可能是
used somewhat more often,
使用较为频繁，
and whereas the multivariate Gaussian
而多元高斯
distribution is used somewhat
分布用的有点
less but it has the advantage of being
少，但它具有的优势在于
able to capture correlations between features. So
能够捕捉功能之间的相关性。所以
suppose you want to
假设你想
capture anomalies where you
捕捉异常，你
have different features say where
有不同的特征如
features x1, x2 take
特征为x1，x2等
on unusual combinations of values
不同的值的组合。
so in the earlier
因此，在早期的
example, we had that example where the anomaly was with the CPU load and the memory use taking on unusual combinations of values, if
例如，我们有这样的样本，其中的异常是与CPU的负载，并采取对价值观的不同寻常的组合，内存使用，如果
you want to use the original
要使用原始
model to capture that, then what you
模型捕捉到这一点，那么你
need to do is create an
需要做的是创建一个
extra feature, such as X3
额外的特征，如X3
equals X1/X2, you know
等于X1/X2，你知道
equals maybe the CPU load divided by the memory used, or something, and you
也许等于CPU的负载所使用的内存，还是分了，你
need to create extra features
需要创建额外的特征
if there's unusual combinations of values
如果有的同的值组合
where X1 and X2 take
其中X1和X2取
on an unusual combination of
在一个不同的组合
values even though X1 by
值，即使通过X1
itself and X2 by itself
本身和X2本身
looks like it's taking a perfectly normal value. But if you're willing to spend the time to manually
看起来像它采取了完全正常的值。但是，如果你愿意花时间去手动
create an extra feature like this,
创建这样一个额外的特征，
then the original model will work
那么原始模型将工作
fine.  Whereas in contrast, the multivariate Gaussian model can automatically capture
得很好。而与此相反，多元高斯模型可以自动捕获
correlations between different features. But the original model has some other more significant advantages, too, and one huge
不同特征之间的相关性。但原始模型有一些其他更显著的优势，比如
advantage of the original model
利用原始模型
is that it is computationally cheaper, and another view on this
在于，它在计算上是便宜的，并且另一方面
is that is scales better to
是尺度比较好
very large values of n
当n是个非常大的值
and very large numbers of
和非常大的数字
features, and so even
特征，并且因此即使
if n were ten thousand,
如果n分别为10000，
or even if n were equal
甚至如果n是等于
to a hundred thousand, the original
十万，
model will usually work just fine.
原始模型通常会工作得很好。
Whereas in contrast for the multivariate Gaussian model notice here, for
而与此相反，多元高斯模型在这里，
example, that we need to
例如，我们需要
compute the inverse of the matrix
计算该矩阵的逆矩阵
sigma where sigma is
sigma是
an n by n matrix
一个n×n矩阵
and so computing sigma if
所以要计算出sigma，如果
sigma is a hundred thousand by a
sigma是一个十万了
hundred thousand matrix that is going to be very computationally expensive.
十万矩阵，该矩阵将是非常耗时的计算。
And so the multivariate Gaussian model
这样一来，多元高斯模型
scales less well to large
尺度不那么大
values of N. And
N的和值
finally for the original
最后，关于
model, it turns out
原始模型，事实证明
to work out ok even if
就ok了工作，即使
you have a relatively small training
你有一个比较小的训练
set this is the small unlabeled
集这是小的未标记
examples that we use to model p of x
样本我们用来对模型P(x)来建模
of course, and this works fine, even if
当然，这工作得很好，即使
M is, you
M的值是，你
know, maybe 50, 100, works fine.
知道，也许50，100，工作得很好。
Whereas for the multivariate Gaussian, it
而对于多变量高斯分布，它
is sort of a mathematical property
是一种数学性质
of the algorithm that you must have m
你必须有m
greater than n, so that the number of examples is greater than the number of features you have. And there's a mathematical property of the way we estimate the parameters
大于n，因此，样本的数目是大于的特征数的。还有的，我们估计参数的方法的数学属性
that if this is not true, so if m is less than or equal to n,
如果这是不正确的，因此，如果m小于或等于n，
then this matrix isn't even invertible, that is this matrix is singular, and so you can't even use the
那么这个矩阵甚至不是可逆的，即该矩阵是奇异的，所以你甚至不能使用
multivariate Gaussian model unless you make some changes to it. But a
多元高斯模型，除非你做一些修改。但
typical rule of thumb
这个典型的规则
that I use is, I will use the
我用的就是，我将使用
multivariate Gaussian model only if m is much greater than n, so this is sort of the
多元高斯模型仅当m是大于n大得多，所以这是一种
narrow mathematical requirement, but
狭隘的数学要求，但
in practice, I would use
在实践中，我会用
the multivariate Gaussian model, only
多变量高斯模型，只
if m were quite a bit
如果m是有点点
bigger than n.  So if
大于n大。所以，如果
m were greater than or
m大于或
equal to 10 times n, let's
等于10 n次，让我们
say, might be a reasonable rule of thumb, and if
比方说，可能还是一个合理的经验法则，如果
it doesn't satisfy this, then the multivariate Gaussian model
它不满足这一点，那么多元高斯模型
has a lot
有很多
of parameters, right, so this covariance matrix sigma is an n by n matrix,
的参数，所以这个协方差矩阵sigma是一个n×n矩阵，
so it has, you know, roughly
所以，你知道的，大概
n squared parameters, because it's a symmetric matrix,
n平方的参数，因为它是一个对称矩阵，
it's actually closer to n squared
它实际上更接近到n的平方
over 2 parameters, but this is a
以上2个参数，但是这是一个
lot of parameters, so you need
很多的参数，所以你需要
make sure you have a fairly
确保你有一个相当
large value for m, make sure you have enough data to fit all these parameters. And m greater than
大的值给m，请确保您有足够的数据，以适应所有这些参数。m大于
or equal to 10 n would be a reasonable rule of thumb to make sure that you can estimate this covariance matrix sigma reasonably well.
或等于10 N将是一个经验合理的规则，以确保您能够估计这个协方差矩阵sigma还算不错。
So in practice the original
因此在实践中，原始模型
model shown on the left that is used more often.
显示上左边的更常用。
And if you suspect that you
如果您怀疑自己
need to capture correlations between features
需要捕捉特征之间的相关性
what people will often do is just manually design extra features like these to capture specific
人们会经常做的只是手动设计像这些额外的特征来捕捉特定
unusual combinations of values. But in problems where you
值的不同寻常的组合。但问题在那里你
have a very large training set or m is very large and n is
有一个非常大的训练集或m是非常大的，n是
not too large, then the multivariate Gaussian
不要过大，那么多元高斯
model is well worth considering and may work better as well, and can
模型是非常值得考虑，可能更好地工作为好，并能
save you from having to
节省您不必
spend your time to manually
花你的时间来手动
create extra features in case
在情况下创建额外的特征
the anomalies turn out to be captured by unusual
异常变成了异常被捕获
combinations of values of the features.
的特征值的组合。
Finally I just want to
最后，我只是想
briefly mention one somewhat technical
简要地提一个有点技术
property, but if you're
属性，但如果你
fitting multivariate Gaussian
拟合多元高斯
model, and if you find
模型，如果你发现
that the covariance matrix sigma
该协方差矩阵sigma
is singular, or you find
是奇异的，或您发现
it's non-invertible, they're usually 2 cases for this.
它是不可逆的，他们通常是两种情况。
One is if it's failing to
其一是如果它未能
satisfy this m greater than
满足这个m大于
n condition, and the
n的条件，以及
second case is if you have redundant features.
第二种情况是，如果你有多余的特征。
So by redundant features, I mean,
因此，通过多余的特征，我的意思是，
if you have 2 features that are the same.
如果你有2个特征是相同的。
Somehow you accidentally made two
不知怎的，你不小心做了两个
copies of the feature, so your x1 is just equal to x2. Or if you have redundant features like maybe
该特征的拷贝，所以你的X1正好等于2倍。或者如果你有多余的特征，如可能
your features X3 is equal to feature X4, plus feature X5.
你的特征X3是等于X4的特征，再加上特征X5。
Okay, so if you have highly
好了，所以如果你有高度
redundant features like these, you
多余的特征，如这些，你
know, where if X3 is equal
知道，其中如果X 3是相等
to X4 plus X5, well X3
到X4加X5，X3以及
doesn't contain any extra information, right?
不包含任何额外的信息，对不对？
You just take these 2 other features, and add them together.
你只需要这2个其他的特征，并把它们相加。
And if you have this
如果你有这样的
sort of redundant features, duplicated features,
多余特征，重复特征，
or this sort of features, than sigma may be non-invertible.
或这样的特征，sigma可以是不可逆的。
And so there's a debugging set--
所以有一个调试设置 -
this should very rarely happen,
这应该很少发生，
so you probably won't run into this,
所以你可能不会遇到这个，
it is very unlikely that you have to worry about this--
它是不太可能，你不必担心这一点 -
but in case you implement a
但如果你实现一个
multivariate Gaussian model you find that sigma is non-invertible.
多元高斯模型，你发现，sigma是不可逆的。
What I would do is first
我会做的是第一
make sure that M is quite
确保M比
a bit bigger than N, and if it
N大很多，如果它
is then, the second thing I
然后，第二件事情我
do, is just check for redundant features.
这样做，只是检查多余特征。
And so if there are 2 features
所以，如果有2个特点
that are equal, just get rid
这是相等的，只是去掉
of one of them, or if
其中之一，或者如果
you have redundant if these
你有多余的，如果这些
, X3 equals X4 plus X5,
，X3等于X4加X5，
just get rid of the redundant
刚刚去掉多余的
feature, and then it should work fine again.
特征，那么它应该正常工作。
As an aside for those of you
顺便说一句，对于那些你们
who are experts in linear algebra,
线性代数专家，
by redundant features, what I
通过多余的特征，我
mean is the formal term is
意思是先前的方程的
features that are linearly dependent.
特征是线性相关的。
But in practice what that really means
但在实践中是什么真正含义
is one of these problems tripping
是这些问题的难为
up the algorithm if you just make you features non-redundant.,
你的算法，如果你只是让你的特征非多余。，
that should solve the problem of sigma being non-invertable.
应该解决的sigma是不可逆的问题。
But once again
但再次
the odds of your running into this
你的遇到这个的概率
at all are pretty low so
在所有都相当低，因此
chances are, you can
这样的机会，你可以
just apply the multivariate Gaussian
只是采用了多元高斯
model, without having to
模型中，而不必
worry about sigma being non-invertible,
担心sigma是不可逆的，
so long as m is greater
只要m为大于
than or equal to n. So
小于或等于n。所以
that's it for anomaly detection,
这是它的异常检测，
with the multivariate Gaussian distribution.
用多元高斯分布。
And if you apply this method
如果你将这个方法
you would be able to have an
你将能够有一个
anomaly detection algorithm that automatically
异常检测算法，自动
captures positive and negative
捕获正和负
correlations between your different
您的不同特征之间的相关性
features and flags an anomaly
和标志异常
if it sees is unusual combination
如果它认为是不寻常的组合
of the values of the features.
的特征的值。